cwjobs.co.uk 2016-04-12

# Privacy policy

_Privacy policy last updated: 1 December 2015_.

This privacy policy applies only to this website (the “Site”). The Site is operated by Totaljobs Group.

We are part of the  [ StepStone GmbH ](https://www.stepstone.com/privacy-statement) group of companies (the “StepStone Group”). StepStone is a global online job board company that operates online job portals to accurately match candidates with companies. 

At CWJobs.co.uk we make every effort to comply with our obligations under the Data Protection Act 1998. Additionally, we understand the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of your CV and other information stored about you while using the site.

You can remove any of the information that CWJobs.co.uk stores about you, at any time, by logging in to your 'My CWJobs.co.uk' account and choosing to close the account.

By using the Site you consent to the collection and use of information in accordance with this privacy policy. Privacy policy to be updated 1 December 2015.

** Collection of Personal Information  **

We collect personal information from you (for example, name, address, telephone number, email address, photo etc) when you make an application, complete registration forms, submit comments to the Site, participate in message boards, blogs or any other user generated content facilities or send emails to us. We may also extract relevant personal information from other data that you provide, for example, from your CV. Please do not submit such personal information to us if you do not wish us to collect it. 

We may also collect personal information which we have found from other websites that display information about you publically. For example, social media accounts such as Facebook and Twitter, your online profile on your current employer’s network, any articles about you or any public listing of your profile. 

** Registration details **

Contact and other details you supply as part of the registration process are stored by us and used to provide you with the information you have requested. Please note that although we require customers who use our services, such as employers seeking to recruit staff, to agree to use the information made available solely for recruitment-related purposes, we do not control their use of any information that they have access to as part of receiving our services.

** Profile and CV information **

When you complete your CWJobs.co.uk profile, including your CV, it can be made available for searching and viewing over the Internet, including other company recruitment sites within the StepStone Group, and downloading by any direct recruiter, employment consultant or other person or organisation who requests CVs matching your profile to be sent to them. CWJobs.co.uk does not verify the identity or the nature of the business of such organisations.

** IMPORTANT NOTICE: ** Your current employer may be a customer of CWJobs.co.uk, or a client of one of our customers. CWJobs.co.uk cannot restrict the customers who access profiles on our database and cannot be held responsible for any eventuality. As part of the registration process CWJobs.co.uk offers you the option of remaining anonymous.

CWJobs.co.uk will also use the aggregate data to identify employment trends across different industries, such as salary averages. This information will not be capable of being linked to any personally identifying information about users.

Some of our customers may be located in countries outside the European Economic Area.

When you 'apply online', we store some information about you in your 'My CWJobs.co.uk' area, but it is protected by your password and may only be accessed by you. When your profile is searchable your application activity (number of applications, job titles, locations & salaries) will be visible to CWJobs.co.uk customers. CWJobs.co.uk does not verify the names of organisations you applied to. We will respect the choices you make to limit sharing or visibility settings in your “My CWJobs.co.uk” account. You can delete your 'My CWJobs.co.uk' account at any time, make your profile anonymous or choose to not make your profile searchable. Your CV can only be viewed by a CWJobs.co.uk customer, or customer of the StepStone Group, if you have consented to this within the profile section.

If you choose to create a profile and upload a CV to our database, we rely on you to ensure that your details are kept up to date. You should update your CV at least every six months, particularly if your contact details have changed.

Please note that CWJobs.co.uk reserves the right to remove from our database, CVs which include any content that we consider to be illegal or offensive.

** IP address information **

Like many websites, we routinely capture your IP address information to determine your location. An IP address, or 'internet protocol address', is a unique identifying number given to every device connected to the internet. Like a car license plate, an IP address is a special serial number used for identification. This helps us work out whether you are visiting the site from within the UK, EU or rest of the world, and means we can show you content that's specific to your location and ask the right questions about your eligibility to work in the UK or EU should you wish to apply for a job on CWJobs.co.uk.

** Statistical information **

We provide aggregate statistical information about site visitors and users to recruiters (such as the number of CVs on the database, or the number of visitors to the site) and for other lawful purposes. We provide this information to customers, advertisers, suppliers and other reputable third parties. This will not include any information that enables them to identify individuals.

** Location based services  **

If you use the CWJobs.co.uk mobile phone app we will ask you if you want to use our geolocation service. This service is provided by Adobe Systems Software Ireland Limited. Based on your mobile phone GPS signal it allows us to identify your location. We will use this information to provide you with job offers close to you and to improve our services. In no case will we merge such information with any personally identifiable information. We will at no times be able to connect you personally in connection with the respective location. You may at any stage opt out of location tracking by changing the app settings to not allow the app to access your location data. However, you will also lose the location supported product functionality as well. For further information about Adobe and their service please visit [http://www.adobe.com/privacy.html](http://www.adobe.com/privacy.html).

** Push notifications **

If you use the CWJobs.co.uk website or mobile phone app, you may also consent to push notifications, text messages, alerts, emails or other types of messages directly sent to you outside or inside of the CWJobs.co.uk mobile phone app to your mobile device or desktop browser. If you declare your consent to receive such messages a device token will be generated, which will be associated with your device. These device tokens will be stored on our behalf by Notice Software, Inc d.b.a Roost, 234 5th Ave, New York, NY 10001. You can opt out from receiving such messages by changing the settings of your device.”

** Online Behavioural Advertising **

We partner with third-party advertising networks to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. These ad network partners may utilise cookies or web beacons to better provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you. They do not collect and do not have access to any personally identifiable information. They may, however, anonymously track your Internet usage across other websites in their networks beyond these Sites. To learn more about the use of this information or to choose not to have this information used by our third-party advertising partners by opting out please visit the Network Advertising Initiative by clicking [networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) or visit their privacy statements: [Google](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/policies/technologies/ads/), [Adobe](http://www.omniture.com/en/privacy) and [Krux](http://www.krux.com/krux_privacy/consumer_choice).

** Sharing Your Information  **

Personal data which you supply to us may be transferred to third party service providers to be stored or processed on our behalf, including third parties located outside of the European Economic Area in countries where there may be a lower legal level of data protection. However, we will always endeavour to handle your information in accordance with this privacy policy, wherever it is processed.

Personal data which we collect from both public sources and from yourself may also be shared with other companies within the StepStone Group. This may include your job seeker profile and result in your profile being searchable on other company sites within the StepStone Group. At all times, the StepStone Group companies will ensure that your information is adequately protected. Each member of the StepStone Group may use and share your personal information as set out in this privacy policy. In accordance with the type of services you have registered for, requested, and the functionality you use, we will disclose your personal information for a prospective job. 

** Security **

We take the security of your personal information very seriously and have appropriate technical and organisational measures in place. The site is protected against unauthorised access using the latest security devices and 'firewalls'.
